Dănilă, Petrișor-Alexandru

Phone: (+4) 0729 89 26 27 E-mail: <u>alex.danila@gmail.com</u>

Date of birth: 15.04.1985

Profile:

Software engineering master's graduate, with experience in procedural and object oriented programming, especially using C++, C and the Qt4 toolkit.

I'm interested especially in developing applications with an important algorithmic component, and which may have scalability requirements, developed in languages such as C++, Python, Haskell.

Technical competencies

Programming:

- C++ (2 years with Qt 4)
- C
- Python
- Haskell
- C#, Java

Operating system use: Linux (Debian, SUSE), Windows (XP, Server 2003) Scripting: Bash

Professional experience

August. 2014 – present C++, Python programmer

Gameloft, Bucharest

- Dev lead in the QA automation project
 - $\circ\quad$ Design and program the C++/Qt5 tool which collects data for quality assurance
- Developer in the Android team:
 - Worked on porting Age of Sparta from iOS to Android (project integration)
 - Android build system maintenance
- Member of the crisis squad:
 - Implemented server-side security in World at Arms (Python)
 - Evaluated and fixed problems in the networking side of Immortal Odyssey

Feb. 2014 – May 2014 QML, C++ programmer Continental, Timișoara – project based contractor on behalf of Luxoft Bucharest

- Developed/improved automobile Human Machine Interface applications using Qt Quick and OML:
 - Rewrote visibility conditions of the application's visual elements from imperative to declarative, to enable animations of each of them
 - Bug fixing and component upgrades management

Jul. 2011 – Nov. 2013 C,C++,C# programmer Ixia, Bucharest

- Developer in the Ixia Virtual Machine simulator project (C++, C, POSIX, kernel modules). I acted as the multi-platform person in the team.
 - Implemented Linux ioctls for serialising Ixia network packet definitions
 - Modified Libvirt and libvirtc application model to work with many network interfaces
 - Implemented the resource accounting part of the VM simulator
- Developer in the IxAnalyzer team (C++, C#):
 - Expanded the Ixia packet capture agent to use circular buffers and mark lost packets
 - Expanded the capture agent and desktop application to support reconnection
 - Helped a junior accommodate with work on IxAnalyzer
- Developer in the Log Collector team (C, Python, C#).
 - Multi-threaded the Python component to improve performance and stability
 - Offered support on Linux related issues to the team specialised in Windows development
 - Stabilised the log collector on server side: write test programs that triggered all log collector functionality, triggered performance limitations and also acted as documentation for all features

Nov. 2009 – Jul. 2011 C++,C# programmer Misys TCM, Bucharest

- Developer in the Summit Multiplatform project.
 - During this project we ported Summit applications, previously running on Solaris 32 bit/SPARC32 and Windows 32 bit/X86, to also run on Solaris 64 bit/SPARC64, Linux 64 bit/X86-64 and Windows 64 bit/X86-64.
 - Modified the build system to compile Summit, which included:
 - modified all build scripts to accommodate the new platforms
 - compiler flags and linker flags
 - options to cleanly exclude from build 3rd party software without multiplatform support
 - dealing with GNU ld quirks
 - Fixed pointer arithmetic to run on all platforms
 - Fixed memory corruptions that did not trigger wrong behaviour on 32 bit platforms
 - Dealt with performance problems: alignment and process model

- Developer in the Summit Architecture team:
 - Implemented new features in Java, C++ and C#
 - Integrated projects to/from different releases

Feb. 2008 – Aug. 2008

Movidia, Timișoara

C++,assembly programmer

- Evaluated the Movidia VLIW hardware architecture: analysed which sets of instructions could be hardware implemented, based on the needs of standard physics algorithms
- Implemented parts of the Movidia assembler (C++); among them, the mathematical expression evaluator.

Jul. 2007 – Sep. 2007

Freescale Romania, Bucharest

Student intern in the CodeTEST team

• Improved the CodeTEST build system with heuristics to guess correspondence between release versions (Python, Bash and Perl programming)

Oct. 2004 - Oct. 2005

AIESEC, Timisoara

Volunteer in the sales team

Member in the team establishing relations between AIESEC and IT companies in Timişoara

Education

2008 - 2009

International School for Informatics, Hagenberg, Austria

Master of software engineering

Thesis with the title "Enhancing 3D Modeling Software for Inline Quality Control"

2004 - 2008

Mathematics and Computer Science college West University of Timisoara

Bachelor of Computer Science

Thesis with the title "Indexer - developing a desktop search engine"

Foreign languages

English – advanced

French – average